Curriculum Vitae

Richard J Fox

Address: 10 Oxhey Lodge, Manor Road, Harrow, HA1 2PB

Nationality: *British* DOB. 17/10/1985

Email: rjfox321<at>gmail.com Mobile: 07745556901

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Software Developer with a wide skill base, 4+ years experience and a passion for games development. Experienced in mobile games development with a published game on the app store. Additionally I have worked on small web based games using GWT/GAE and HTML5 canvas, military training/simulation software, stock management and EPOS systems with SQL database design, development and maintenance.

Long term aim: specialise in AI or games engine development.

EMPLOYMENT

• Worldweaver Ltd (October 2011 – September 2012)

Software Developer

Tasks –Mobile games development in small teams for IOS using Xcode, Objective-C and cocos2d. Tools programming in the form of a level editor using C# and XML. Windows based cross platform mobile development using cocos2d-x, C++ and VS2010. Military simulation and training software development in a larger team using existing in-house games engine including some SQL database design and development and supporting C# codebase. Development of unreleased Google Web Toolkit(GWT) / Google App Engine (GAE) games including use of HTML5 canvas.

• Esperus Systems Ltd (April 2010 – October 2011)

Developer

Tasks – Lead developer maintaining the 'Genesis' stock management system, Optimisation of slow functions/queries, liaising with testing and support teams on bugs and client feedback, Req/Spec of additional Genesis development requests, C# Tools/Utilities, full development lifecycle of new internal bug, development & call logging system (C#), Data Warehousing, Com interop, Development of SQL data structures updater, Assist development of .Net web services and applications, Crystal reports design and development, SVN server setup and maintenance.

• Esperus Systems Ltd (June 2008 – April 2010)

Junior Developer / Support Engineer

Tasks – Assist maintaining existing 'Genesis' windows based retail/wholesale stock management system code base. Vb6/vb.net, Crystal Report 9+ reports, UI design, MS SQL 2005+ database design, deployment and administration, client requirement gathering/analysis, client training seminars, network and vpn installs, customer care and support.

EDUCATION

University of Lincoln (Sept 2004 – July 2007)

BSc (Hons) Software Development (Games Computing)

A computer science degree with an opportunity to specialise into games / graphics technology towards the latter part of the course. Focus on C++ with 3D graphics (OpenGL), mobile games programming in Java and HL2 Source games engine.

SEEVIC College, Benfleet, Essex (Sept 2002 – July 2004)

A 'Level Business Studies - Grade A

A' Level Computing - Grade B

A' Level Psychology - Grade C

King Edmund School, Rochford, Essex (Sept 1997 – July 2002)
11 GCSE's including Math, English, Science, IT, Business.

OTHER SKILLS

- C++, C#, Java, VB6, VB.NET, Object Orientated Programming
- Objective-C, IOS, Cocos2D/-X, Box2D
- Direct X 9, OpenGL, HLSL and related 3D maths.
- Google Web Toolkit, HTML5 Canvas, XML, Jjavascript
- Visual Studio 2005, 2008, 2010, VS6, Eclipse, Xcode, debugging.
- MS SQL Server 2005, 2008, TSQL, Database Design, Administration.
- Database programming including ADO/.net
- WinAPI and STL.
- Source Control GIT, SVN, Mercurial, VSS.
- Software Engineering theory, testing theory
- 3D content creation (3d Studio Max), 2D content creation (Photoshop CS, Flash)

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- 3D Graphics/Games development projects using DirectX & C++. Ongoing development of a hobbyist 3D games engine.
- Website/Forum programming challenges.
- New technology and gadgets.
- Gaming, Music, Guitar, Martial Arts.

REFERENCES

Mr C Sterling CEO and Founder Worldweaver Ltd Pinewood Studios Iver Heath, Bucks 01753 656 884 Mr B Chambi Office Manager Esperus Systems Itd 288 Chase Road Southgate, London. 0208 920 9888